准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
跳探戈
动干戈
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
海之霸
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday on you
今天真是你生日
It's your birthday, it's true
也是我创造你的那天
It's the day that I built you
祝你生日快
Happy birthday on
谢尔顿啊
Oh, Sheldon
今天是我过的最棒的一次生日了
This has been the best birthday I've ever had
还没完呢
And it ain't over yet
现在要来让寿星拆礼物了
It's time for the birthday girl to open her presents
哒哒
Ta-da
是探戈课的礼品券
It's a gift certificate for tango lessons
虽然我是很愿意与你共舞  亲爱的
You know I'd love to dance with you, sweetie
但我们以前试过了
but we've tried this before
还记得
And if you recall--
跳得都不怎么顺利
It did not go well
这一次就不一样了
This time is going to be different
因为另外一样生日礼物就是这个
Because your other birthday present is this
超级无敌拉腿机
The Leg Yanker Five Zillion
都是为了你  宝贝
This is for you, baby
天气不错吧
Nice weather up here
你好啊  绿色邪恶高个儿
Well, hello, tall, green, and evil
能与你共舞吗
May I have this dance?
裤头村活动中心
苏西格鲁夫舞蹈学校
晚上七点半
好爱你的长腿新模样  痞老板
Love the new stems, Plankton
都已经晚上八点了
It's 8:00 p.m. already
舞蹈老师呢
Where's our dance instructor?
同学们好
Hello, class
我是你们的舞蹈老师  苏西格鲁夫
I'm your tango instructor, Susie Groove
等我教完
And when I'm done with you
你们的舞步就会变成这样
this is how you gotta move
大家开始跳舞吧
So everyone start dancing
我会来给大家指导几下
and I'll come around and give you some tips
你第一条规矩就违反了  宝贝
You're breaking the first rule, honey
一个探戈两人跳
It takes two to tango
[ 一个巴掌拍不响 ]
抱歉  格鲁夫老师
Sorry, Miss Groove
蟹老板要求我
Mr. Krabs ordered me
今晚来当珍珍的探戈舞伴
to be Pearl's tango partner tonight
但她好像不太喜欢我的猛烈舞步
but she just doesn't dig my tangy moves
海绵宝宝  你不会跳探戈
SpongeBob, you can't tango
我要的可是真正的舞伴
I need a real dance partner
不是精力过剩  腿还打结的白痴
not a cackling, bow-legged goofball
无意冒犯
No offense
我就当你是在夸我
I took it as a compliment
我可以教会大家跳探戈
I can teach anyone to tango
只要你
All you gotta do is
你会跳探戈了
You can tango
多亏有苏西格鲁夫
Thanks to Susie Groove
跳探戈不可以靠太近
That's too close to tango
一二三
One, two, three
放松点  谢尔顿
Relax, Sheldon
我尽力了  跳舞小能手
I'm trying, my little whirling dervish
可我这双腿不听使唤
but these legs have minds of their own
别乱来  白痴
Not that way, you idiots
你们可恶
Damn you
镇静一点  亲爱的
Compose yourself, darling
这可是公共场合
We're in public
我知道
I know
我只是需要有个东西来帮我平衡
I just need something to balance me
看吧
See?
这就行了
It works
等等  我能行
Wait, I got it
我能行
I got it
别跳了
Stop dancing
抱歉  苏西
Sorry, Susie
我刚洗过腿  结果腿不听使唤了
I just washed my legs, and I can't do a thing with them
问题不在于腿  宝贝
Legs ain't your problem, honey
要是想跳探戈  就要学会
If you want to tango, you got to learn
用臀部去跳
to dance with your hips
用唇部吗
With my lips?
没什么用啊
This isn't working
因为我说的是臀部
That's because I said hips
看好了
Watch me
你就只要
All you got to do is
你臀部还挺不俗
Your hips are so hip
这下你有得辛苦了  谢尔顿
You got your work cut out for you, Sheldon
我的臀部又做不到
My hips can't do that
当然做得到了
Of course they can
你必须迫使臀部跳下去
You got to force them to do it
跳探戈要身心皆备
The tango is physical, emotional
而且最重要的是  要霸道
and most importantly, aggressive
什么
What?
霸道
Aggressive?
这么一说我就懂了
Now you're talking my language
对啊  我们可会霸道了
Yeah, we speak fluent aggression
好
Good
那就多多利用霸道  施加在臀部上
Tap into that aggression and put it in your hips
来紧紧相拥
Now, abrazo
抱紧了
Embrace
紧紧相拥
Abrazo
好了吗
Ready?
你就只要
All you gotta do is
跳得真不错  痞老板夫妇
Terrific tangoing, Planktons
对啊
Yeah
本来以为我们跳得好呢
I thought we were good
你们这一说可真好心
How nice of you to say
紧紧相拥吧  我的臭奶酪
Abrazo, my stinky cheese
紧紧相拥吧  我的烂玫瑰
Abrazo, my rotten rose
不好了  我一不小心把钉条弄掉了
Oh, no, I accidentally dropped my spike strip
哎呀
Oopsie
我们就是探戈王与探戈后
We're the king and queen of tango
痞老板夫妇  休息一下吧
OK, Planktons, take four
痞老板跟凯伦刚刚有点坏啊
That wasn't very nice of Plankton and Karen
确实挺坏
No, it wasn't
但那就是探戈  宝贝
but that's the tango, honey
跳得好  痞老板夫妇
Bravo, Planktons
霸道得真不错
Nice aggression
谢谢  苏西
Thank you, Susie
打磁盘碎片整理以来就没这么开心过
I haven't had this much fun since I got defragged
我觉得我们就是全班第一
I'd say we're the best in the class
你说呢  格鲁夫老师
wouldn't you, Miss Groove?
我觉得你们两个都很棒
I think you're both great
但我的尖子生也许会不同意哦
but my top students might disagree
尖子生
Top students?
对啊
Yeah
他们今天迟到了
They're late today
探戈大师到了
The tango masters have arrived
抱歉迟到了
Sorry we're late
海霸王得换条干净内裤
Bubble Bass needed clean underwear
老妈
Mother
海霸王和他妈
Bubble Bass and his mom?
没错
That's right
我跟老妈已经赢了海底探戈锦标赛
Mother and I have won the Undersea Tango Championship
连续三年了
three years in a row
我们最强
We're the best
但是不知怎的  毫无预兆
But yet somehow, and without warning
我们才最强
we're the best
斗舞的气息扑面而来
I smell a dance-off
昆虫优先
Insects first
哒哒
Ta-da
来跳赢我们啊
Well, try and out-tango that
那我们就跳了
Don't mind if we do
我说我们最强
I said we're the best
紧紧相拥
Abrazo
看来有谁点了霸王三明治
Looks like someone ordered a Bass sandwich
虽然很有趣
Well, that was fun
但我们似乎还不够霸道
But I guess we're not aggressive enough
称不上最强
to be the best
谁都不可能比我们还霸道
Nobody is more aggressive than us
他们就只是练得多而已
They just have more practice
要是能有办法作弊就好了
If only there was some way we could cheat
让他们见识一下谁最强
and show them who's really the best
还是回去吧  谢尔顿
Let's just go home, Sheldon
给  这个从你口袋里掉出来了
Here, this fell out of your pocket
是我的瑞瑞射线
It's my Ray-Ray ray
可以把我变成
the device that turns me into
发型更帅的另一个人格  瑞瑞
my alter ego with great hair, Ray-Ray
这样我就可以更霸道了
That'll make me more aggressive
还真是  痞老板
You're right, Plankton
只有我的瑞瑞可以掌控全局
My Ray-Ray is the only one who could take charge of this
不要动
Hold still
在下瑞瑞  宝贝
It's Ray-Ray, baby
抱歉  射错老头了
Sorry, wrong old man
在下瑞瑞  宝贝
It's Ray-Ray, baby
看来有谁点了份冰冷的复仇大餐
Looks like someone ordered a cold plate of revenge
而且还要把脸丢光
With extra humiliation
探戈重赛  宝贝
Tango rematch, honey
不要
No
加油  瑞瑞
Go, Ray-Ray, go
虽然我想恨痞老板夫妇
I want to hate the Planktons
但他们也太强了
but they're so good
没事没事
There, there, there
他跳舞的样子好像天使
He dances like an angel
死亡天使
Of death
以探戈赋予我的权力
By the tango vested in me
我正式宣布凯伦与瑞瑞
I pronounce Karen and Ray-Ray
是我的尖子生  宝贝
my top students, honey
成功了  瑞瑞
We did it, Ray-Ray
我们最强
We're the best
生日快乐  凯伦小可爱
Happy birthday, Karen-cakes
世界之巅
top of the world
现在来收尾
Now for the big finish
不好了
Oh, no
摩擦力太强了
Too much friction
我的
My--
我的腿
My legs
抱歉  那是我的台词
Sorry, that's my line
给  痞老板
Here, Plankton
可以借用我的腿
you can borrow my legs
不用了
No, thanks
我的已经长回来了
Mine are growing back already
谢谢  凯伦
Thank you, Karen
一个探戈两人跳
It takes two to tango
过来吧  瑞瑞
Come here, Ray-Ray
在下瑞瑞  宝贝
The name's Ray-Ray, baby
食灵之书
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
裤头村
咖啡壶
我好爱早餐
I just love breakfast
早餐钱花得再多也没关系
I don't mind overpaying if it's breakfast
这钱看得我垂涎三尺
That money looks tasty
能别闹了吗
Do you mind?
抱歉
Sorry
这么多吃早餐的  看得我又饿又渴
All these people eating breakfast is making me hungry
渴望多来一点客人
Hungry for more customers that is
说到客人  别来烦我客人
Speaking of customers, stop bothering mine
蟹堡王
这一踢开启了我的全新一天
Well, that sure kick-started my day
早安  蟹老板
Morning, Mr. Krabs
早安  蟹堡王的员工们
Good morning, Krusty crew
我有个金点子要用在蟹堡王上
I have a fantastic idea for me restaurant
要去月球开蟹堡王吗
We're opening a Krusty Krab on the moon?
要永远关门了吗
We're closing down forever?
什么
What?
不对
No
从现在起  蟹堡王要开始供应早餐了
From now on, the Krusty Krab
will start serving breakfast
你们两个要更早来上班
And you two get to come to work even earlier
好啊  我可以做蟹黄堡当早餐了
Oh, boy, I get to make Krabby Patties for breakfast
不对不对不对
No, no, no, no, no
大家才不会一大早来吃蟹黄堡
People don't want patties in the morning
大家会想吃培根煎蛋和薯饼
They want bacon and eggs and hash browns
就那种一般的早餐
You know, breakfast stuff
看看你能不能当场做一份煎饼  小子
See if you can whip up a stack of pancakes, boy-o
好的  老板
Yes, sir
吃一口看看质量如何  章鱼哥先生
Give it the old mouth test, Mr. Squidward
这煎饼味道像蟹黄堡
These pancakes taste like a Krabby Patty
看来我只会做蟹黄堡
I guess I only know how to cook Krabby Patties
我就怕这种事
I was afraid of this
快去一趟书店
Go down to the bookstore
把我预订的早餐菜谱取回来
and pick up the breakfast cookbook I ordered
得让你的本领稍微增进一点点  小子
You need to expand your repertoire a bit, boy-o
书
你好  我来帮蟹老板取食谱
Hello, I'm here to pick up a cookbook for Mr. Krabs
那当然了  先生
Well, of course, sir
早餐魔法
作者  吉米叔叔
拿去吧
Here you go
你确定就是这本书吗
Are you sure this is the right book?
看着差不多
Looks right to me
不好意思
Pardon me
这起司男孩挺有礼貌
What a polite little hunk of cheese
我先前订了本书  暂存在这
I have a book on hold
订购者姓女巫  名邪恶
last name Witch, first name Evil
好的
Certainly
一定就是这本
Must be this one
你的书  女士
Your book, ma'am
我忘戴眼镜了
I forgot my spectacles
你确定就是我订购的魔法书吗
Hey, buddy, you sure this is the magic book I ordered?
非常确定
Pretty sure
你说是就是
If you say so
蟹堡王               正在供应早餐
我取到菜谱了  蟹老板
I got the cookbook, Mr. Krabs
快点  小子
Hurry up, boy-o
要知道早餐可不会整天供应
Breakfast don't last all day, you know
爱情魔药
爱情魔药  召唤恶魔
Love potions, summoning demons
恶魔召唤
与亡灵共存
the undead and you
早餐
Breakfast
悲苦一大叠
"Stacks of woe"
意思一定就是煎饼
That must mean pancakes
书上要求的材料也太诡异了
This book sure calls for some weird ingredients
蟹老板  有没有僵尸牙
Mr. Krabs, do we have any zombie teeth
龙息  蝾螈眼
dragon's breath, eye of newt?
冰库最里面应该就有一些
Well, there should be some in the back of the freezer
有这回事
Really?
咋了
What?
促销可不能错过
I can't pass up a sale
找到了
Found them
必须在大铁锅里面煮
Must be cooked in an iron cauldron
有格调
Classy
里面应该就有一个
I think there's one in here somewhere
找到了
There you are
好漂亮
They're glorious
看着挺好吃
Looks tasty
章鱼哥先生  再来试吃一口
Mr. Squidward, you're up again
这做得还不错
Say, these are pretty good
早餐上菜了
Breakfast is served
麦片来了  先生
Your oatmeal, sir
清淡又好吃
Deliciously bland
我上午起来就为了这个吗
I woke up before noon for this?
我的早间营养哪去了
Where is my morning sustenance?
你的华夫饼来了
Your waffles
最可口的食粮
A meal most toothsome
来付早餐钱
Time to pay for my repast
不会吧  我的屁股发癫了
Egad, my hindquarters have gone rogue
已经不止冒犯到我了
I am beyond offended
谁点了冻糕
Who ordered the parfait?
果然
Of course
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
这到底是怎么一回事
What the ham and eggs is going on around here?
我貌似还没摸清早餐的门道  蟹老板
I don't think I've got the hang
of this breakfast thing, Mr. Krabs
一杯牛奶
A cup of milk?
两颗蛋
Two eggs?
一条面包
A loaf of bread?
还有海草糖
And kelp sugar?
好吧
All right
法式吐司
French toast?
薯饼
Hash browns?
乳蛋饼
Quiche?
辣煎蛋卷
Huevos rancheros?
怎么回事
What the heck?
这破烂咒语书什么毛病
What's wrong with this blasted spell book?
吉米叔叔早餐魔法
"Uncle Jimmy's Breakfast Magic"?
这就是本菜谱
It's a cookbook
得尽快找出是谁误拿了我的咒语书
I better find out who got my spell book, and fast
不过得先把乳蛋饼吃了
Right after I finish my quiche
怎么会这样
Why is this happening?
可能都是我煮的诡异东西害的
Maybe all the weird stuff
I've been cooking caused all of this
所以怪不得还要用到大铁锅
Would explain the cauldron too
还有会飞的菜谱
And the flying cookbook
菜谱利用早餐美食
The cookbook is using tasty breakfast treats
创造出了大怪物
to create a monster
原来我的咒语书到这来了
So this is where my spell book went
有客人
A customer
帮她接单  章鱼哥
Take her order, Squidward
谢了  不过我早就吃不下了
Thanks, but I couldn't eat another bite
我是来找你换书的
I'm here to swap books with you
我的咒语书好像跟你的菜谱搞混了
I think my spell book got mixed up with your cookbook
但得先把食物闹出来的惨剧解决掉
But first, I better take care of this foodie fiasco
食物食物变变变
Flippity floppity food
怎么会是枫糖浆
Not maple syrup
我黏住了
I'm sticky
太黏了
So sticky
你  手拿魔杖的海绵小子
Hey, you, the spongy kid with the wand
那是锅铲
That's a spatula
我的魔杖
My wand
我把法力稍微借你一用
Well, I'll lend you some of my magic
要想阻止早餐  唯有派出它的死对头
The only way to stop breakfast is with its mortal enemy--
晚餐
dinner
我会做晚餐
I can do dinner
蔬菜炖肉炖炖炖
Pippity poppity pot roast
不对
No
章鱼哥可不是均衡早餐的一部分
Squidward is not part of a balanced breakfast
来个三层蟹黄堡
a triple-decker Krabby Patty
多加奶酪
With cheese
我得度个假
I need a vacation
小子  想当我的徒弟吗
Hey, kid, do you want to be my apprentice?
你可有魔法天赋了
You got a real knack for magic
谢了
Thanks
但我唯一需要的魔法就只有
But the only magic I need is
蟹黄堡的美味
the delicious taste of a Krabby Patty
蟹黄堡肉饼
A patty?
现在吃有点早了
It's a little early for me
除非
Unless
蟹黄堡华夫饼
A Krabby waffle
蟹黄堡华夫饼是吗
A Krabby waffle, eh?
我又有个金点子了
I have another brilliant idea
再也不供应早餐了
We will no longer be serving breakfast
从现在起  蟹黄堡供应早晚餐
From now on, the Krusty Krab will be serving "brinner"
早餐晚餐合在一起
The breakfast-dinner duo
这次我亲自去取了新菜谱
And this time, I picked up the new cookbook myself
来客人了
We've got customers